In love and war the first casualty is truth
Guernica is a drama, war, romance film directed by Koldo Serra.
The fates of Henry - an American correspondent - and Teresa, one of
the Republic's censors during the Spanish Civil War.
Henry, played by James D'Arcy.
Teresa, played by María Valverde.
Vasyl, played by Jack Davenport.
María (as Natalia Álvarez), played by Natalia Álvarez-Bilbao.
Cousin Isabel, played by Irene Escolar.
Consul, played by Burn Gorman.
Guernica (Spanish/Basque: Gernika) is a 2016 Spanish-British-American war romance drama film
directed by Koldo Serra, starring James D'Arcy, María Valverde and Jack Davenport.
It is the first feature film made about the 1937 bombing of Guernica.
The film centres on an American journalist (D'Arcy) covering the Spanish Civil War, and the bombing of
Guernica, who falls in love with a censor (Valverde) for the Spanish Republican government.
The journalist's character is loosely based on George Steer, a British reporter who covered the
war and bombing for the UK media, as well as Ernest Hemingway and Robert Capa.
The film explores themes of journalist, spain, civil
war, based on true story, nostalgic.
The tone is emotional.